Jeremy L. Shepherd

Full Stack Developer

Xenia, Ohio

937.475.2375

github.com/jeremylshepherd jeremylshepherd.github.io

About Me

How I got into coding

In 2014, I wanted to have a website to showcase my photography. I started with WordPress templates but never found one that spoke to me. I decided to learn enough coding to build my own webpage. Eventually, I landed on Codecademy's site. I took one class, then two, then three... until I had taken nearly every course on the site. I was hooked and have been since. I have expanded my knowledge and built several projects. I enjoy the challenge of solving problems with code.

Tech Summary

ReactMongoDB

React NativeSQL

AngularRuby-on-Rails

NodeJSExpressFirebase

Current Projects

- Building a Completely Cross-Platform update to a citation tracking application built for Good Samaritan Hospital Campus Police. The updated application will be deployed at all Premier Health Campus Police Departments. I am building it using React-Native and React-Native-Web.
- Contributor to <u>create-react-native-web</u> (Open Source)

Professional Experience

2003-Present Good Samaritan Hospital Dayton, OH

Campus Police Officer (Sergeant)

- Promoted to Sergeant in 2008
- · Managed a small team of professionals
- Built the citation tracking application now used by the department.

1999–2006 Cedarville Police Dept. Cedarville, OH

Police Officer

Functioned with limited direct supervision in a field that demands a high level of accountability

1999–2000 Wilberforce Univ. Police Dept. Wilberforce, OH

Campus Police Officer

• Functioned with limited direct supervision in a field that demands a high level of accountability

Education

- Senior, BCJ Program (Ohio University, Inactive)
- AAS Criminal Justice (Sinclair Community College)
- Free Code Camp Completed Full-Stack Curriculum.